<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Assignments on HIS393: Digital History</title>
    <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/assignment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Assignments on HIS393: Digital History</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 14:35:21 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://digitalhistory.github.io/assignment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 03: DOM and Data</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/assignment/03-dom-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 14:35:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/assignment/03-dom-data/</guid>
      <description>Due Date: October 25
In this assignment, you will slowly work your way up to manipulation of real web pages via Javascript. This can be a difficult transition, so be prepared for some teeth-gnashing.
Due at end of the day on the due date, you can find the asssignment link on Github, and please be sure to create your own copy and clone the resultant repository to your laptop. (Don&amp;rsquo;t search out and fork the parent repository!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 02: Javascript Basics</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/assignment/02-js-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 22:36:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/assignment/02-js-basics/</guid>
      <description>Due Date: Oct. 08
This assignment introduces you to the third and most interesting pillar of basic web development: Javascript.
Due at end of the day on the due date, you can find the asssignment on Github and clone the resultant repository to your laptop.
Rubric Passes General Tests Passes Reflection Tests -  -
-</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 01: Zero to Blog Post</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/assignment/01-html-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 11:36:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/assignment/01-html-css/</guid>
      <description>Due Date: Sept. 26 (2 days later than original deadline)
General Description You do not have to become a coder to do well in this course. However, you will have to be willing to explore technical skills that you might not otherwise develop as a humanities scholar. In this second assignment, we&amp;rsquo;ll use one of the web&amp;rsquo;s many excellent self-education platforms to learn the very basics of how web pages work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 00: Your Class Profile</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/assignment/00-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 13:12:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/assignment/00-git/</guid>
      <description>General Description If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for History, Please, follow that link! Your job in this assignment is to tell the class a few things about yourself. In the process we&amp;rsquo;ll think about a few issues related to digital storage of information, including privacy, interpretation of sources, and data vs. knowledge.
One of the hardest parts of this course for many people is setting up their working environment. In this assignment you will be need to set up your working environment and then use Git, much as we did in class, but this time manipulating the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participation</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/assignment/participation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 13:10:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/assignment/participation/</guid>
      <description>As described in the syllabus, I use your participation mark to determine the &amp;ldquo;-/null/+&amp;rdquo; part of your grade. Let me explain a little more explicitly how this works.
The System It&amp;rsquo;s simple. Suppose you successfully complete all the main assignments, but decide not to write a Project Proposal. Congratulations! You have qualified for a B. But what kind of a B?
   If your class participation was: You get a: Which ROSI will show as:     Poor B- 72   Satisfactory B 75   Excellent B+ 78    Similarly, perhaps you were only able to complete the Git &amp;amp; Github, HTML &amp;amp; CSS, Javascript and Oral History.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>