<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HIS393: Digital History</title>
    <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on HIS393: Digital History</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:59:33 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://digitalhistory.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 00: Your Class Profile</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/posts/00-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:59:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/posts/00-git/</guid>
      <description>General Description If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for History, Please, follow that link! Your job in this assignment is to tell the class a few things about yourself. In the process we&amp;rsquo;ll think about a few issues related to digital storage of information, including privacy, interpretation of sources, and data vs. knowledge.
One of the hardest parts of this course for many people is setting up their working environment. In this assignment you will be need to set up your working environment and then use Git, much as we did in class, but this time manipulating the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:22:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/setup/</guid>
      <description>For the duration of this course, you will need to set up a &amp;ldquo;development environment&amp;rdquo; to do your work. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to download,install, and interact with a group of programs and services that make it possible to do your work. Setting your environment up can be difficult, so be sure to budget some time to do so! Also be aware that these tools will take up significant spae on your laptop and may cause your laptop to slow down somewhat if run simultaneously with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>using vscode</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/using-vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:22:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/using-vscode/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Visual Studio Code is an amazing general-purpose code editor. Most people I collaborate with use it as their primary editor, and that will be true in most professional settings you enter. This is the first year we&amp;rsquo;re using it in the class, and I have some high hopes for it.
As with any powerful tool, it can take a little while to get comfortable with VSCode. The documentation is excellent, but may sometimes assume more advanced programming skills than you have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating at the Command Line</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/navigating-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:22:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/navigating-command-line/</guid>
      <description>The Programming Historian link below is excellent. Having some trouble with screenshots ATM, will fix soon as I can reload my desktop &amp;#x2013; but for next few hours pls refer to the PH link for images!
One common issue for people new to the command line is that it can be tough to understand the notion of location in the filesystem. Most ordinary users interact with their filesystems through the so-called GUI layer &amp;#x2013; the graphical interface of windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Node Dependencies</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/node-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:03:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/node-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>Node.js is an exquisite piece of programming infrastructure. One of its main features is support for developer-defined dependencies. As a programmer &amp;#x2013; or in my case, as a teacher &amp;#x2013; you can inform the underlying node package manager (npm) that your project &amp;ldquo;depends&amp;rdquo; on some group of other projects. This allows programmers to build constantly on each other&amp;rsquo;s work.
In our assignments, node dependencies are mostly used to enable the tests, whose main function is to help you figure out whether you&amp;rsquo;ve done the assignments correctly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>header</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/_header/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/_header/</guid>
      <description>HIS 393 Digital History</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/slides/01-02-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/slides/01-02-git/</guid>
      <description>01-02: Git and Github .underline { text-decoration: underline; }   /* Position computations of klipse get confused by reveal.js&#39;s scaling. Hence, scaling should be disabled with this code. Fix height of code area with scrollbar (use overflow instead of overflow-y to restore CodeMirror setting afterwards): */ .reveal section pre { max-height: 70vh; height: auto; overflow: auto; } /* Reset some reveal.js and oer-reveal settings: */ .reveal section pre .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/slides/01-intro-digital-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/slides/01-intro-digital-history/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Digital History .underline { text-decoration: underline; }   if( window.location.search.match( /print-pdf/gi ) ) { var link = document.createElement( &#39;link&#39; ); link.rel = &#39;stylesheet&#39;; link.type = &#39;text/css&#39;; link.href = &#39;../../vendor/reveal//css/print/pdf.css&#39;; document.getElementsByTagName( &#39;head&#39; )[0].appendChild( link ); }    Introduction to Digital History Matt Price  (view this presentation in another theme: Black (default) - White - League - Sky - Beige - Simple Serif - Blood - Night - Moon - Solarized )	--   About Me    Historian of Science &amp;amp; Technology Interdisciplinary Background Interest in &amp;ldquo;Engaged&amp;rdquo; scholarship     Why Care about History?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/syllabus/his393syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/syllabus/his393syllabus/</guid>
      <description>Logistics    Instructor: Matt Price     Email: matt.price@utoronto.ca   Meeting Times T Th 2-3, SS 1070   Web: http://digitalhistory.github.io/   Slack: https://digitalhistoryuoft.slack.com/   Office Hrs: T Th 3-3:30, SS 3077    In general, online communication should take place via Slack. In the case of questions having to do with official University business (requests for extensions, discussion of accommodations, any message involving sensitive personal data) please use my University email, being sure to put &amp;ldquo;HIS393&amp;rdquo; in the subject line.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>