<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HIS393: Digital History</title>
    <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on HIS393: Digital History</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://digitalhistory.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/syllabus/his393syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 13:05:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/syllabus/his393syllabus/</guid>
      <description>Logistics    Instructor: Matt Price     Email: matt.price@utoronto.ca   Meeting Times T Th 10-12 EST via BB Collaborate   Web: http://digitalhistory.github.io/   Slack: https://digitalhistoryuoft.slack.com/   Youtube: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC59evpoPsmdKhmB9YeqXMPg   Office Hrs: T Th 3-3:30, SS 3077    In general, online communication should take place via Slack. In the case of questions having to do with official University business (requests for extensions, discussion of accommodations, any message involving sensitive personal data) please use my University email, being sure to put &amp;ldquo;HIS393&amp;rdquo; in the subject line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12: Citizen History</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/slides/12-citizen-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 11:56:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/slides/12-citizen-history/</guid>
      <description>Reminders  Oral History due shortly Proposal due immediately after sorry no snacks!  What we&amp;rsquo;ve learned Text is Code  all our work is &amp;ldquo;digital&amp;rdquo; now  The 3 layers of the web  structure presentation dynamism  The &amp;ldquo;Public&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;the Public Sphere&amp;rdquo;  media constrain the possible the &amp;ldquo;public&amp;rdquo; is probably not unitary don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a genius to make a contribution  Invocations and Incantations  Using APIs to take advantage of other people&amp;rsquo;s work writing only what you have to  Open and Closed Systems  what &amp;ldquo;open source&amp;rdquo; means for us  Maps and Legends  organizing stories around space digital maps are spcial  Storytelling  the distinctive features of oral history problems of truth and objectivity collaboration and authorship  What you might do History doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to stop at graduation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Popcorn</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/understanding-popcorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 15:16:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/understanding-popcorn/</guid>
      <description>You may find it useful, as you prepare for the next assignment, to read the following post!
What is Popcorn Popcorn is a Javascript &amp;ldquo;library&amp;rdquo; – a small collection of programs – that lets web designers key events in a web page to a time-code in a media file. So essentially, popcorn lets you &amp;ldquo;cue up&amp;rdquo; content ad display it only during fixed periods, while a media element is playing. If you then pause or manually rewind/fast-forward the media element (audio or video), the events will also reset to the appropriate time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JS Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/js-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 15:23:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/js-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>Jquery and Vanilla JS equivalents:
   Task jQuery &amp;ldquo;Vanilla&amp;rdquo; JS     Get all matching elements $(&#39;selector&#39;) document.querySelectorAll(&#39;selector&#39;)   Get first matching element $(&#39;selector&#39;).first() document.querySelector(&#39;selector&#39;)   Change CSS prop $(&#39;selector&#39;).css(&#39;property-name&#39;, &#39;value&#39;) document.querySelector(&#39;selector&#39;).style.property-name = &#39;value&#39;     const matches = document.querySelectorAll(&#39;selector&#39;)     for (const m of matches) {m.style.property-name=&#39;value&#39;   Change Text Value $(&#39;selector&#39;).text(&#39;new text here&#39;) document.querySelector(&#39;selector&#39;).textContent = &#39;new text here&#39;     const matches = document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distant Reading</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/slides/05-02-distant-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:06:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/slides/05-02-distant-reading/</guid>
      <description>Recap  &amp;ldquo;Public sphere&amp;rdquo; at a turning point Transformation by automated agents and encoded text  War is Peace. Freedom is Slavery. Ignorance is Strength. Plan for the day  Problems of Abundance Distant Reading: a method for textual overload? Discussion: how do you respond to information abundance? post-class period ONLY for students who failed the tests, or did not receive a mark  History in the age of scarcity  The members of prehistoric societies did not think they lived in prehistoric times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript: Resources and Tools</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/js-resources-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 22:32:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/js-resources-tools/</guid>
      <description>Resources There are many, many excellent JavScript resources on the web. I strongly recommend the MDN JavaScript Learning Pathway. I also have a very high opinion of Eloquent Javascript, but in past years students have often found it somewhat difficult. However, it rewards careful study, teaches excellent habits, and encourages creative thinking while coding. Both MDN and EJ have built-in JS Consoles forexperimenting with code (see below).
MDN also has a more advanced guide to JavaScript which starts with this &amp;ldquo;reintroduction&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participation</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/assignment/participation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 13:10:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/assignment/participation/</guid>
      <description>As described in the syllabus, I use your participation mark to determine the &amp;ldquo;-/null/+&amp;rdquo; part of your grade. Let me explain a little more explicitly how this works.
The System It&amp;rsquo;s simple. Suppose you successfully complete all the main assignments, but decide not to write a Project Proposal. Congratulations! You have qualified for a B. But what kind of a B?
   If your class participation was: You get a: Which ROSI will show as:     Poor B- 72   Satisfactory B 75   Excellent B+ 78    Similarly, perhaps you were only able to complete the Git &amp;amp; Github, HTML &amp;amp; CSS, Javascript and Oral History.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:22:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/setup/</guid>
      <description>For the duration of this course, you will need to set up a &amp;ldquo;development environment&amp;rdquo; to do your work. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to download,install, and interact with a group of programs and services that make it possible to do your work. Setting your environment up can be difficult, so be sure to budget some time to do so! Also be aware that these tools will take up significant spae on your laptop and may cause your laptop to slow down somewhat if run simultaneously with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>using vscode</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/using-vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:22:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/using-vscode/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Visual Studio Code is an amazing general-purpose code editor. Most people I collaborate with use it as their primary editor, and that will be true in most professional settings you enter. This is the first year we&amp;rsquo;re using it in the class, and I have some high hopes for it.
As with any powerful tool, it can take a little while to get comfortable with VSCode. The documentation is excellent, but may sometimes assume more advanced programming skills than you have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating at the Command Line</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/navigating-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:22:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/navigating-command-line/</guid>
      <description>The Programming Historian link below is excellent. Having some trouble with screenshots ATM, will fix soon as I can reload my desktop – but for next few hours pls refer to the PH link for images!
One common issue for people new to the command line is that it can be tough to understand the notion of location in the filesystem. Most ordinary users interact with their filesystems through the so-called GUI layer – the graphical interface of windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Node Dependencies</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/node-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:03:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/tools/node-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>Node.js is an exquisite piece of programming infrastructure. One of its main features is support for developer-defined dependencies. As a programmer – or in my case, as a teacher – you can inform the underlying node package manager (npm) that your project &amp;ldquo;depends&amp;rdquo; on some group of other projects. This allows programmers to build constantly on each other&amp;rsquo;s work.
In our assignments, node dependencies are mostly used to enable the tests, whose main function is to help you figure out whether you&amp;rsquo;ve done the assignments correctly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>header</title>
      <link>http://digitalhistory.github.io/_header/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://digitalhistory.github.io/_header/</guid>
      <description>HIS 393 Digital History</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>