<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HIS393: Digital History</title>
    <link>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/</link>
    <description>Recent content on HIS393: Digital History</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>header</title>
      <link>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/_header/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/_header/</guid>
      <description>HIS 393 Digital History</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 00: Git and Github</title>
      <link>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/00-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 21:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/00-git/</guid>
      <description>General Description If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for History, Please, follow that link!
One of the hardest parts of this course for many people is setting up their working environment. In this assignment you will be need to set up your working environment and then use Git, much as we did in class, but this time manipulating the command line.
This may take longer than you think, and it&amp;rsquo;s due soon. Please get started soon by following the instructions on the Assignment 0 website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 01: HTML &amp; CSS self-study</title>
      <link>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/01-html-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 21:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/01-html-css/</guid>
      <description>Due Date: Jan. 26
General Description You do not have to become a coder to do well in this course. However, you will have to be willing to explore technical skills that you might not otherwise develop as a humanities scholar. In this second assignment, we&amp;rsquo;ll use one of the web&amp;rsquo;s many excellent self-education platforms to learn the very basics of how web pages work. We&amp;rsquo;ll then extend that knowledge with a set of slightly more advanced programming exercises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 02: Javascript Basics</title>
      <link>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/02-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 21:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/02-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Due Date: Feb. 02</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 03: Spatial History</title>
      <link>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/03-spatial-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 21:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/03-spatial-history/</guid>
      <description>Due Date: March 02
In class, we made a kind of toy Google Map out of hand-coded HTML, CSS, and Javascript. You will remember it from the course website, from JSBin, and from Github.
Your next assignment builds directly from that in-class exercise, and should be quite a bit easier to manage, technically, than your last assignment. Essentially, you will repeat the in-class assignment with much greater intellectual effort, but using the same technical framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 04: Oral History</title>
      <link>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/04-oral-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 21:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/04-oral-history/</guid>
      <description>Due Date: March 29
Rather than repeat myself in my usual error-prone way, I will simply direct you to the assignment repository on Github. We will discuss this at great er length in class in the final weeks of the semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 05: Project Proposal</title>
      <link>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/assignment-05-project-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 21:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/assignment-05-project-proposal/</guid>
      <description>Due Date: April 02
For your final assignment, respond to the following call for proposals with an application approximately 2000 words in length, plus a provisional budget i n the form of a spreadsheet. See below for details.
Call for Proposals: Digital History Initiative Grants The Hacking History Foundation is pleased to announce a new Digital History Initiative, intended to advance the field of digital historical studies in Canada. We are grateful to an anonymous donor from Qatar who has agreed to underwrite three levels of grant:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participation</title>
      <link>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/participation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 21:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/participation/</guid>
      <description>As described in the syllabus, I use your participation mark to determine the &amp;ldquo;-/null/+&amp;rdquo; part of your grade. Let me explain a little more explicitly how this works.
The System It&amp;rsquo;s simple. Suppose you successfully complete the Git &amp;amp; Github, HTML &amp;amp; CSS, Javascript, Spatial History, and Oral History assignments. Congratulations! You have qualified for a B. But what kind of a B?
   If your class participation was: You get a: Which ROSI will show as:     Poor B- 72   Satisfactory B 75   Excellent B+ 78    Similarly, perhaps you were only able to complete the Git &amp;amp; Github, HTML &amp;amp; CSS, Javascript and Oral History.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/syllabus/his393syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/syllabus/his393syllabus/</guid>
      <description>Logistics    Instructor: Matt Price     Email: matt.price@utoronto.ca   Office Hrs: T 1-2:30, SS 3077   Meeting Times Thurs 2-4, SS 1088   Web: http://digital.hackinghistory.ca/   Slack: https://digitalhistoryuoft.slack.com/    In general, communication should take place via Slack. In the case of questions having to do with official University business (requests for extensions, discussion of accommodations, any message involving sensitive personal data) please use my University email, being sure to put &amp;ldquo;HIS393&amp;rdquo; in the subject line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup</title>
      <link>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/tools/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 13:48:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/tools/setup/</guid>
      <description>For the duration of this course, you will need to set up a &amp;ldquo;development environment&amp;rdquo; to do your work. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to download,install, and interact with a group of programs and services that make it possible to do your work. Setting your environment up can be difficult, so be sure to budget some time to do so! Also be aware that these tools will take up significant spae on your laptop and may cause your laptop to slow down somewhat if run simultaneously with</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>