<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Assignment on HIS393: Digital History</title>
    <link>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/tags/assignment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Assignment on HIS393: Digital History</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 16:37:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/tags/assignment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 03: DOM and Data</title>
      <link>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/03-dom-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 16:37:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/03-dom-data/</guid>
      <description>Due Date: March 01
In this assignment, you will slowly work your way up to manipulation of real web pages via Javascript. This can be a difficult transition, so be prepared for some teeth-gnashing.
Due at end of the day on the due date, you can find the asssignment on Github, and please be sure to check out your own copy (as per the instructions) by following the link as soon as it goes live, and cloning the resultant repository to your laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 00: Your Class Profile</title>
      <link>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/00-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 13:37:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://digitalhistory.github.io/dh-website/assignment/00-git/</guid>
      <description>General Description If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for History, Please, follow that link! Your job in this assignment is to tell the class a few things about yourself. In the process we&amp;rsquo;ll think about a few issues related to digital storage of information, including privacy, interpretation of sources, and data vs. knowledge.
One of the hardest parts of this course for many people is setting up their working environment. In this assignment you will be need to set up your working environment and then use Git, much as we did in class, but this time manipulating the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>